

ALEXANDER DOVNAR

DEVOPS SPECIALIST (LEAD\ARCHITECT)

ABOUT ME

Highly motivated engineer with good level of experience in modern technologies and approaches in IT world in common and DevOps particular.

My daily intent is to make the world around me better. In my work I strict to automate as much as possible, because I know that human make mistakes.

I love my family, like the soccer and X-Box games from time to time

CONTACTS

- Belarus, Minsk
- dovnar.alexander@gmail.com
- +375 (44) 763-25-73
- in /aliaksandrdounar
- https://dovnar-alexander.xyz

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree: BSUIR (Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics) - Informational technologies and management in technical systems

College: Belarus State Academy of Communication - Technicianprogrammer in the Networking

KEY SKILLS

- Certified AWS architect (Professional)
- Good skills in almost all modern DevOps tools and practices.
- Good at designing and implementation of CI\CD pipelines
- I do everything as code (IaC, CM, Kubernetes ...)

EXPERIENCE

EPAM Systems (www.epam.com) Lead Systems Engineer

APRIL 2016 - NOW

- Has grown from a Junior Systems engineer to the Lead position
- Worked on different projects on different roles as: Team and Technical Lead, Maintenance and Build engineer.
- Designed, lead and supported the development process of the automation code for Infrastructure and Software provisioning with Ansible, Packer and Terraform following Immutable infrastructure approach.
- Decreased the delivery pipeline for multiple projects minimum on 40% (Jenkins\Java\SonarQube).

Technologies:

Ansible AWS GCP Terraform Packer Git Vagrant Kubernetes EKS KOPS Bash Python Linux Windows Jenkins GitLabCI Travis NewRelic Zabbix Grafana EKL Elasticsearch Prometheus Docker

CERTIFICATES

- HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate (<u>Link</u>)
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect
 Professional (<u>Link</u>)
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect
 Associate (<u>Link</u>)
- Google Cloud Platform Professional Cloud Architect (<u>Link</u>)
- Cisco CCNA

КОНТАКТЫ

- Беларусь, Минск
- dovnar.alexander@gmail.com
- +375 (44) 763-25-73
- in /aliaksandrdounar
- https://dovnar-alexander.xyz

EXPERIENCE

Freelance (www.dovnar-alexander.xyz)

SEPTEMBER 2020 - NOW

Different projects in different domains (from several countries)

Technologies:

AWS GitLabCI Terraform Kubernetes EKS Docker Docker-Compose

RUE Beltelecom (www.beltelecom.by) - Senior Engineer

MARCH 2011 - APRIL 2016

- Worked as the 1st and 2nd ISP Client support in the call center. Later was promoted to the network oncall engineer responsible for the backbone ISP network support and maintenance.
- Enterprise clients support (VPN and Ethernet\SHDSL Internet access).
- Initialised and developed multiple automation solution based on scripts for network equipment maintenance.

Techologies:

Huawei Cisco xDSL xPON ISP IPTV VoIP VPN Linux Zabbix